

WEB DEVELOPER

5 Brown Ave, Roslindale, MA, 02131 ieloletin@gmail.com 419.360.2989

SUMMARY: Whether creating full-stack web applications, treating and transporting people having medical emergencies or building and maintaining aquatic exhibits, I am experienced in meeting goals under strict deadlines. I am driven and dedicated to creating products that are practical, functional tools which help simplify people's lives.

Experience

General Assembly / Full-Stack Web Developer in Training

October 2016 - January 2017 | Boston, MA

Built full-stack applications during a 12-week web development immersive, by creating and utilizing:

- ➤ RESTful APIs and single-page applications
- Version Control (Git and GitHub)
- User Stories, Wireframes and ERDs
- > Pair programming, working as part of a team and individual coding
- Digital Bookshelf | Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Handlebars, JavaScript, HTML

A personalized review and reading list application for book lovers.

- Watchy McWatchface | MongoDB, Express.js, Handlebars, JS, Node.js

A digital storefront application for consumers in the market for high-end wristwatches.

- Three-Sixty-Five | Ember.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML

A resolution and goal tracking application to document daily progress and help users achieve their goals.

Job Experience

Boston EMS / Emergency Medical Technician

January 2014 - October 2016 | Boston, MA

- ➤ Responded to emergency calls placed via the 9-1-1 system.
- Assessed and treated the diverse population of Boston citizens, according to local and state protocols.
- Administered medication and assisted paramedics with select medical treatments.
- > Transported patients to local hospitals.
- Documented care provided to patients and communicated pertinent information to hospital staff.

New England Aquarium / Aquarist

February 2010 - January 2014 | Boston, MA

- Provided animal husbandry for marine and freshwater organisms through food preparation, feeding, cleaning, assisting with and administering medical treatments and recording observations of animal behavior.
- > Maintained aquatic environmental parameters.
- Interviewed and hired seasonal interns.
- Supervised and trained volunteers and interns in animal handling, collection and husbandry.

Skills		
HTML	CSS	JavaScript
Handlebars	Ruby	Ruby on Rails
JQuery	Node.js	PostgreSQL
Express.js	Git	Ember.js
Bootstrap	SCSS	MongoDB
SQL	AJAX	Mongoose

Education

Northeastern University 2009

Boston, MA

Bachelors of Science: Biology

Code Samples

Portfolio: ariel-n-martin.com

GitHub: github.com/ielole

Interests

- Reading
- SCUBA diving
- Rock Climbing
- Black and White Photography
 - Sustainable Energy
 - Conservation